Aliaksei Sarokin

Python Developer | Warsaw, Poland

With over 8 years of experience in developing, designing, and maintaining web applications, I have developed many different features and solved various problems. Most of the applications I worked on are based on Django and Flask, or built on top of them. I am competent in frontend development and deploying applications to the server. The latest project I worked on was a fairly large e-commerce platform with significant data, extensive code, and many different APIs connected.

Work History

2018-03

- 2024-04

Senior/Lead Python Developer

filterbuy.com, Talladega, Alabama (remotely)

- Maintaining and enriching sales (retail and B2B) along with customer service platforms for USA airfilters brand with almost \$400 millions revenue and thousands transactions daily.
- Developing and maintaining B2B, Sales Representative, and Wholesale Reseller dashboards.
- Integrating payment gateway, shipping, marketing, tax calculation, and other required APIs into the system (like Stripe, FedEx, Klaviyo, etc.).
- Tracking orders and transactions to stay up-to-date by building automation tools and manually tracking "heaviest" orders (up to \$500k).
- Managing and ensuring system performance and stability with a load balancer and monitoring tools.
- Mentoring, guiding, and ensuring code quality for a small team of 1-2 developers.

2016-10

- 2024-04

Middle/Senior Python Developer

CoreTech.io (54origins), Minsk, Belarus

- Developing platform using Salesforce and marketing automation processes like managing duplicates, data normalization, segmentation, enrichment.
- Automatization of data analysis in big set of text documents using parsing tools and background running tasks.
- Designing and implementing various backend systems using Django, DRF and Flask frameworks along with efficient data processing and highperformance APIs.

2015-10

- 2016-10

Junior Python Developer

CoreTech.io (54origins), Minsk, Belarus

- Developing and delivering MVPs for sales and data collecting platforms.
- Building parsing and data collecting marketing tools.
- Implementing RESTful APIs for integration with external services and thirdparty applications.

Education

2010-09

- 2015-06

Electrical, Electronic and Communications Engineering Technology/Technician

Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics

Personal Info

Email

alexxmagpie@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/aliakseisarokin-126916b9/

Phone

48728234312

Skills

Python 2.7/3.10, Django, Django Rest Framework, RESTful APIs, Oscar, Flask, unittest, pytest, Locust, Celery, ELK, Selenium, Scrapy

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, Redis

Docker, AWS, uWSGI, NGINX, Git, Bash

OOP Knowledge, Design Patterns, Well-Structured Communication

Languages

Polish - B1

English - B2

Belarusian - C2

Russian - C2